

Mohamed Younis Abdallah Abdallah

Nationality: Sudanese

Gender: Male

CONTACT



Dubai, UAE. 00000 Dubai, United Arab Emirates (Work)



mohamedyounis150@gmail.c om



(+971) 569802585



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ mohamedabdallah-1760a4307/

ABOUT MF

As an experienced Full Stack Developer, I have a deep understanding of the entire web development process, from front-end development to back-end programming, database management and hosting. I am a creative problem-solver with a focus on delivering user-centered solutions. I am a highly motivated and self-driven individual, with a passion for technology and a commitment to delivering high-quality work. I am open to new opportunities and welcome the chance to connect with other professionals in the industry.

Main Tech Stack: JavaScript, Reac.JS, Angular, ASP.net C#, Node.JS, CSS,

HTML, jQuery, SQL.

Finally, I have strong knowledge in working as data analyst skilled in power BI, Tableau, MySQL, python.

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2022 - 03/2024 Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Software developer ISAP Solutions

- Develop interactive, user-friendly web applications using modern front end technologies (React, or Angular).
- Collaborate with back end developers and designers to implement responsive and visually appealing user interfaces.
- Optimize web applications for maximum speed and scalability.
- Building Back-end Systems: also i work on the server-side of applications, handling tasks such as database interactions, user authentication, and server-side logic. i am using Node.is to server-side.
- Ensure cross-browser and cross-device compatibility.
- · Conduct code reviews, identify areas for improvement, and maintain high-quality coding standards.
- Stay up-to-date with the latest front and back end development trends, tools, and technologies.
- Actively participate in brainstorming sessions and contribute innovative ideas to enhance user experiences.

12/2020 - 09/2022 Kosti, Sudan

Front End developer Almassar charity Organization

- Designed impactful donation websites for Almassar Charity, Kosti, Sudan, focusing on refugee support.
- Collaborated on user-friendly interfaces using React IS for dynamic and responsive web experiences.
- Conducted usability tests and ensured cross-browser compatibility.
- Worked closely with back-end developers and contributed to coding standards.
- Stayed updated on industry trends to enhance design projects.

01/2020 - 12/2020 Khartoum, Sudan

Front End developer Enigma

- Drove React IS development at Enigma, Khartoum.
- Translated requirements into dynamic web interfaces for optimal user experience.
- Collaborated on seamless integration and maintained coding
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and contributed to project planning.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

12/2020 Khartoum, Sudan

Bachelor (HONORS) in Mathematics and Computer Science. University Of Khartoum

Website www.uofk.edu

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Arabic

Other language(s):

English

Listening C1 Spoken production C1
Reading C1 Spoken interaction C1
Writing C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

React JS, React Route, React Hooks, React Dom | Angular | JavaScript | TypeScript | (C++ & C#) | Node.js / Express | Html5 & CSS3 | Bootstrap 4 & 5 | Git | .NET (Entity Framework) | CI /CD | RESTful api | Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL | iaaS/PaaS/SaaS | ES5 - ES6 | Testing/Debugging | agile method | Mongodb / Mongoose | Go/Golang | Python With Data Science Language | Data Visualization tools (Tableau, Excel, Power BI)

PROJECTS

T2meen webSite

The website displays the services and prices of the largest Sudanese insurance companies.

Vehicle insurance, travel insurance, fire insurance, medical insurance, agricultural insurance...et

Link https://t2meen.com/

Mahmall

A site for buying and selling used mobile devices.

The site allows the user to upload pictures and specifications of the used device to display it to other users.

Link https://ae.mahmall.com/ar

CryptoVerseHub

CryptoVerseHub is Built on the robust foundation of React and SCSS, allows users to search for information about various cryptocurrencies in real-time.

Link https://crypto-currency-verse-hub.netlify.app/

COURSES

01/12/2015 - 01/01/2016

CCNA Certificate.

Preparatory course for CCNA.

25/05/2021 - 16/06/2021

Electronic Accounting

Electronic Accounting content on (Excel Advance, QuickBooks and Odoo.